Vignesh S

Engineer 2, Software Development & Engineering

vignesh020600@gmail.com 9092213009 https://www.linkedin.com/in/vignesh-s-20a7911a4/LinkedIn

I am an Enthusiastic Professional Software Engineer with proven experience in planning, requirements gathering, designing, developing, testing, demonstrating to clients and upper management, and deploying software. I have experience in all areas of the development process and believe I can adapt to any environment

WORK EXPERIENCE:

TeleApps Private Limited - Software Engineer.

October 2022 - current

- Developed robust, reusable, and reliable platform components, modules and services that enhanced the web application contact center product with modules like Web soft phone, User Management, Reports, Dashboards, Outbound Campaign, Settings. Improved Overall Performance.
- Integrated web APIs from Node.js backend, Integrated events from the backend phone to the client for web phones, enhancing the user experience and functionality and Implemented various features related to contact center.
- Tested ,Debug and fixed critical issues using tools to stabilize the web application, ensuring a smooth user experience.
- Handled Linux server for configuring backend applications such as Node.js and FreeSWITCH (phone). Configured ssl certificates to establish secure web applications.
- Delivered products on time with the team, efficiently handling edge-cutting challenges and solving critical problems under pressure. Improved Company Revenue.
- Demonstrated excellent communication skills by presenting demos to higher management and clients, showcasing the product's features and functionality.

TeleApps Private Limited - Software Engineer Trainee..

October 2021 - October 2022

- Developed Frontend modules using Angular, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS for a variety of projects.
- Collaborated with team members and senior developers to build an R&D web application contact center product.
- Implemented modules including dashboards, reports, reactive forms, CRUD operations, and a web soft phone.
- Automated test cases using the Robot Framework to improve development efficiency.
- Maintained codebase using GitLab, ensuring code quality and version control.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS:

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Angular
- Node.js
- React
- TypeScript
- Git
- Linux

EDUCATION::

Vel Tech Multi Tech- B.E Engineering 2017 - 2021 batch 7.0 CGPA. Avadi Chennai -53.